

#### **About Me**

At 25 I have 6 years of Front End Development experience and a Computer Science BSc (Hons) from one of Londons top universities. I'm a driven and enthusiastic developer specialising in pixel perfect, responsive web applications. I have worked for global companies and small agencies, so am happy working with a team, leading a team or working by myself.

## Knowledge

Languages HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery, React, GraphQL, PHP, Twig

Content Management Systems WordPress, Craft CMS, Contentful

Toolkit Visual Studio Code, GitKraken, CodeKit, FileZilla, Sequel Pro, MAMP

Pro, Postman, Photoshop, in Vision, Zeplin, Jira, Google Tag Manager,

Google Analytics, Slack

Operating Systems Comfortable with all versions of Mac OS and Windows

### **Employment History**

Dauntless - Epsom, Surrey Lead Web/UI Developer

September 2015 - Present (Promotion from Front End Web Developer, September 2017)

Lead a team of developers to produce a broad range of digital applications and websites.

- Lead the custom development of all WordPress and Craft CMS websites
- Development of multiple React applications, lead the team responsible for all UI components
- · Worked with and advised the design team on latest digital trends, and best practices
- · Helped put together scope of works and proposals in order to help win work opportunities
- Met clients face-to-face for meetings and training purposes, including international clients
- Carried out interviews to hire for our New York and Phoenix offices

Firedog - Old Street, London

Web and UI Developer

September 2013 - August 2015

- Worked with a team of developers and designers to concept, produce and maintain custom WordPress themes, static web pages and email templates
- Production of iOS application using PhoneGap
- Optimization of page speed and SEO
- Training clients on how to use their website
- Designing interactive wireframes



# **Employment History (Continued)**

JVC Pro - Staples Corner, London

**Marketing Executive** 

August 2012 - August 2013

Worked with other members of the team to create engaging marketing material and help populate and test their new website.

- Creation of print and web adverts using Photoshop and InDesign
- Population of content on the website
- Testing of the new website in collaboration with the developers

Waitrose - Worcester Park, London - Fresh Foods Partner September 2009 - August 2013

Knibbs Associates - Reigate, Surrey - Web Designer (Work Experience) September 2009 - October 2009

#### **Education**

BSc (Hons) Business Computing Systems - City University London - 2:1 2011 - August 2015

Work Based Project	1:1 - 74% (Dissertation	1) "To develop a software solution to a real
--------------------	-------------------------	--

clients problem"

**Electronic Commerce** 1:1 - 92% "To produce a website capable of allowing users to

purchase a product online"

Business Systems 1:1 - 76% "Understanding and creating systems to enhance the

success of a Business"

Programming in Java 1:1 - 70% "Developing our skills in the production of Java programs"

IT Security 2:1 - 65.8% "Learning the skills required to identify, prevent and to

preserve the integrity, availability and confidentiality of information

system resources"

**Computation and Reasoning** 2:1 - 62.8% "How to compute solutions, understanding the strengths

and limitations and how to model them"

**Human Computer Interaction** 2:1 - 62% "Study, planning and design of the interaction between

users and computers"

**Networks and Operating Systems** 2:1 - 62% "Understanding the major operating systems components

and system scheduling"



# **Education (Continued)**

4 A Levels Glyn Technology School, Epsom

2009 - 2011

Double IT (B,C) Business Studies (B) History (B)

11 GCSEs Glyn Technology School, Epsom

2007 - 2009 5 As, 5 Bs, 1 C

#### **Interests**

Outside of my work life I like to keep active, I try to go for a run around 3 times a week and enjoy a round of golf whenever the weather permits. I'm also really into cars and try to get to a few car shows each year. Additionally I love exploring, whether that's finding hidden eating spots in London, or travelling further afield and learning about different cultures.

To view my work please see my online portfolio at mattmuirhead.co.uk.

References available upon request.